Register of the Louis Raemaekers Papers and Artwork
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1901-1939. (Box 1-8)
  - Meester, J. de, 1915 (Folder 5: 55)
  - Milington-Drake, E., 1925-1926 (Folder 5: 56)
  - Mock, J. L., 1924-1927 (Folder 5: 57)
  - Mol, H., 1924 (Folder 5: 58)
  - Morgan, J., 1920-1925., See also Library of J. Pierpont Morgan (Folder 5: 59)
  - Morgan, W., n.d. (Folder 5: 60)
  - Morin, Louis, 1918 (Folder 5: 61)
  - Mortier, Raoul, 1917 (Folder 5: 62)
  - Moynihan, Berkeley, 1918-1922 (Folder 5: 63)
  - Münninghoff, Xeno, 1915 (Folder 5: 64)
  - Musée de la Reconnaissance, Bruges, 1936 (Folder 5: 65)
  - Musée Royal de l'Armée, Brussels, 1927 (Folder 5: 66)
  - Musées Royaux des Beaux-Arts de Belgique, Brussels, 1934 (Folder 5: 67)
  - Musei Capitolini, Rome, 1927 (Folder 5: 68)
  - Muspratt, Max., See Liverpool. Lord Mayor
  - Mussolini, Benito, 1927-1936 (Folder 5: 69)
  - N.V. EM. Querido's Uitgevers-Mij, Amsterdam, 1935 (Folder 5: 70)
  - Napoleon, Prince and Princess Clémentine, 1917 (Folder 5: 71)
  - Nash's Magazine, London, 1920 (Folder 5: 72)
  - National Committee for Relief in Belgium, London, 1916 (Folder 5: 73)
  - National Committee of Patriotic Societies, Washington, D.C., 1917 (Folder 5: 74)
  - National Geographic Society, Washington, D.C., 1933 (Folder 5: 75)
  - National Magazine Co., Ltd., London, 1933 (Folder 5: 76)
  - National Security League, New York, 1917 (Folder 5: 77)
  - Nationale Landstormcommissie, s'Gravenhage, 1919-1920 (Folder 5: 78)
  - Nederlandsch Studenten-Werkkamp, Amsterdam, 1935 (Folder 5: 79)
  - Nederlandsche Ambulance te Brussel, s'Gravenhage, 1919 (Folder 5: 80)
  - Nederlandsche Anti-Oorlog Raad, s'Gravenhage, 1915 (Folder 5: 81)
  - Nederlandsche Vereeniging, Brussels, 1922 (Folder 5: 82)
  - Nederlandsche Vereeniging van Weldsdigheid, 1934 (Folder 5: 83)
  - Neuhuijs, Albert, Mrs., 1915 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Neumont, Maurice., See Société des Dessinateurs-Humoristes
  - New East, Tokyo, 1917 (Folder 6: 2)
  - New York American, New York, 1917 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Nicolson, Vita, n.d. (Folder 6: 4)
  - Niepoort, J. van der, 1914 (Folder 6: 5)
  - Niermeijer, J. F., 1918-1922 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Niermeijer, T., 1933 (Folder 6: 7)
  - Nierstrasz, B., 1935 (Folder 6: 8)
  - Nispen tot Sevenaar, O. F. A. M. van, 1930-1932 (Folder 6: 9)
  - Nolthenius, A. C. Tutein, 1916 (Folder 6: 10)
  - Nooy, Jan, n.d. (Folder 6: 11)
  - Northcliffe, Mary, Lady, 1916 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Northcliffe, Lord, 1916-1918 (Folder 6: 13)
  - Nypels, C., 1930 (Folder 6: 14)
  - Oddman, A. N., 1921 (Folder 6: 15)
  - Oeuvre Municipale de Secours aux Prisonniers de Guerre, Lyon, 1918 (Folder 6: 16)
  - Oeuvre Nationale des Invalides de la Guerre, Brussels, 1922 (Folder 6: 17)
  - Oliveira, Alberto d', 1934 (Folder 6: 18)
  - Olivier, K., 1926 (Folder 6: 19)
  - Olivier, S. C. J., n.d. (Folder 6: 20)
  - O'Neill, Flonner, 1917 (Folder 6: 21)
  - O'Neill Sherman, William, 1916-1917 (Folder 6: 22)
  - Ons Huis, Amsterdam, 1934 (Folder 6: 23)
  - Oor, 1928 (Folder 6: 24)
  - Oor, Jacques, 1917 (Folder 6: 25)
  - Oord, R. van, 1929 (Folder 6: 26)
  - Oorlog of Vrede, Amsterdam, 1932 (Folder 6: 27)
  - Oostenbroek, William, n.d. (Folder 6: 28)
  - Opstelten, J. C., 1915 (Folder 6: 29)
  - Overwijn, J. F., 1914 (Folder 6: 30)
  - Paris (France), 1916 (Folder 6: 31)
  - Paris. Préfecture de Police, 1916-1917 (Folder 6: 32)
  - Pathé Frères, Joinville-le-Pont, 1915 (Folder 6: 33)
  - Perry Robinson, Anne, 1917 (Folder 6: 34)
  - Perry Robinson, Harry, 1915-1930 (Folder 6: 35)
  - Pétain, Philippe, 1918 (Folder 6: 36)
  - Peters, John, 1914-1915 (Folder 6: 37)
  - Philadelphia Wellesley Club, Philadelphia, 1917 (Folder 6: 38)
  - Philips S.A. Belge, Brussels, 1934 (Folder 6: 39)
  - Phillips, William, 1921 (Folder 6: 40)
  - Pirenne, Antoine, n.d. (Folder 6: 41)
  - Pito, Harold A., 1922 (Folder 6: 42)
  - Poilus de France, Brussels, 1934., See also Ligue des Poilus de France en Belgique (Folder 6: 43)
  - Poincaré, Raymond, 1915-1932 (Folder 6: 44)
  - Pol, Jan Paul van de, 1916 (Folder 6: 45)
  - Poland. Poselstwo (Belgium), 1925-1935 (Folder 6: 46)
  - Poland. Poselstwo (Netherlands), 1927-1932 (Folder 6: 47)
  - Polvliet, G., 1923 (Folder 6: 48)
  - Ponthière, P. de, n.d. (Folder 6: 49)
  - Portland, Duke and Duchess of, 1916-1917 (Folder 6: 50)
  - Posthumus Meÿjes, W. C., 1933 (Folder 6: 51)
  - Pulchri Studio, s'Gravenhage, 1915 (Folder 6: 52)
  - Pulitzer, Joseph, Jr., 1928 (Folder 6: 53)
  - Pulman, Mr., 1928 (Folder 6: 54)
  - Punch, London, 1917 (Folder 6: 55)
  - R.K. Vredesbond in Nederland, Rotterdam, 1934 (Folder 6: 56)
  - Rademaekers, William H., 1917 (Folder 6: 57)
  - Radersma, N., 1917 (Folder 6: 58)
  - Raeff, H., n.d. (Folder 6: 59)
  - Raemaekers, J., 1914 (Folder 6: 60)
  - Raemaekers, V., 1916 (Folder 6: 61)
  - Raemaekers-Comité, n.d., See also Schaepkens van Riempst, Jules, 1927-1939 (Folder 6: 62)
  - Ralier, Benjamin, 1916 (Folder 6: 63)
  - Ramaekers, P., 1929 (Folder 6: 64)
  - Rath, H., 1914 (Folder 6: 65)
  - Raymakers, J., 1918 (Folder 6: 66)
  - Raymann, A., 1932-1933 (Folder 6: 67)
  - Reading, Lord, 1933 (Folder 6: 68)
  - Reigersman, C. J. A., 1915 (Folder 6: 69)
  - Reinach, Joseph, 1916 (Folder 6: 70)
  - Reintjes, Jacques, 1915 (Folder 6: 71)
  - Rennes, Catherine van, 1922 (Folder 6: 72)
  - Rensburg, E., 1912 (Folder 6: 73)
  - Review of Reviews, London, 1915-1932 (Folder 6: 74)
  - Rhuys Williams, Lt. Col., 1919-1923 (Folder 6: 75)
  - Ridell, Margaret C., 1918 (Folder 6: 76)
  - Rieger, D. B., 1930 (Folder 6: 77)
  - Rijksmuseum, Amsterdam, 1915 (Folder 6: 78)
  - Rittenhouse, John V., 1930 (Folder 6: 79)
  - Robbers, Mr., 1916 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Roberts, H. C., 1917 (Folder 7: 2)
  - Robertson, John, 1917-1918 (Folder 7: 3)
  - Rodin, Auguste, 1916 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Roëll, A., 1918 (Folder 7: 5)
  - Roelofs, Albert, 1915-1919 (Folder 7: 6)
  - Roes, Paul, 1935 (Folder 7: 7)
  - Roger, Capitaine, 1915-1916 (Folder 7: 8)
  - Roggen, N. van, Jr., 1914 (Folder 7: 9)
  - Roode-Heijermans, M. de, 1915 (Folder 7: 10)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Mrs. Theodore, Jr.), 1928 (Folder 7: 11)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1917 (Folder 7: 12)
  - Rouchon, E., 1925 (Folder 7: 13)
  - Royal Academy of Arts, London, 1919 (Folder 7: 14)
  - Royal Society of Literature of the United Kingdom, London, 1916 (Folder 7: 15)
  - Royal Society of Miniature Painters, London, 1916 (Folder 7: 16)
  - Royal West of England Academy, Bristol, 1918 (Folder 7: 17)
  - Ruys de Beerenbrouck, C. J. M., 1924-1933 (Folder 7: 18)
  - Ruyten, A., 1918 (Folder 7: 19)
  - Sackville-West, Victoria, 1917-1919 (Folder 7: 20)
  - St. Marks Church Men's Club, Brooklyn, 1917 (Folder 7: 21)
  - Saintsbury Club, London, 1931-1937 (Folder 7: 22)
  - Samson, W., 1927 (Folder 7: 23)
  - Sato, M. N., n.d. (Folder 7: 24)
  - Sauvage Nolting, Henri de, 1916-1923 (Folder 7: 25)
  - Savage Club, London, 1916 (Folder 7: 26)
  - Schaepkens van Riempst, Jules, 1927-1939 (Folder 7: 27)
  - Schaepman, C. J. M., 1923-1925 (Folder 7: 28)
  - Scheffer, M., 1924 (Folder 7: 29)
  - Schoemaekers, Prosper, Captain, 1915 (Folder 7: 30)
  - Scholl, J. C., 1914 (Folder 7: 31)
  - Schröder, J. C., 1911-1932., See also Holdert (Folder 7: 32)
  - Schwob, Maurice, 1927-1928 (Folder 7: 33)
  - Selborne, Lord, 1915 (Folder 7: 34)
  - Serbian Press Bureau, London, 1918 (Folder 7: 35)
  - Sforza, Count and Countess, 1934 (Folder 7: 36)
  - Sholes, Walter H., 1932-1933 (Folder 7: 37)
  - Shuster, W. Morgan, 1917-1920 (Folder 7: 38)
  - Slothouver, G., 1927 (Folder 7: 39)
  - Sluiter, Willy, 1934 (Folder 7: 40)
  - Snel, N. F., 1914 (Folder 7: 41)
  - Società Leonardo da Vinci, Florence, 1915-1916 (Folder 7: 42)
  - Société des Dessinateurs-Humoristes, Paris, 1916 (Folder 7: 43)
  - Société Nationale des Beaux-Arts, Paris, 1916 (Folder 7: 44)
  - Soir, Le., See Arsac, d'
  - Soissons, 1916 (Folder 7: 45)
  - Sorgen, D. van, 1936 (Folder 7: 46)
  - South Africa. Consulate (Geneva), 1932 (Folder 7: 47)
  - Spaudling, John T., n.d. (Folder 7: 48)
  - Spectator, The, London, 1933 (Folder 7: 49)
  - Steed, H. Wickham, 1933 (Folder 7: 50)
  - Steinlen, T. A., 1901-1916 (Folder 7: 51)
  - Stevens, J. C., 1914 (Folder 7: 52)
  - Stille Rondgang, Harlem, 1934 (Folder 7: 53)
  - Stokvis, H., 1933 (Folder 7: 54)
  - Stuart, Frederik, 1917 (Folder 7: 55)
  - Stuers, A. de, 1916 (Folder 7: 56)
  - Stumm, F. von, Baron, 1915 (Folder 7: 57)
  - Swift, Edward F., 1917 (Folder 7: 58)
  - Swinderen, R. de Mares van, 1909-1929 (Folder 7: 59)
  - Tabak, Bolesław, 1936-1937 (Folder 7: 60)
  - Tabingh Suermondt, B., 1914 (Folder 7: 61)
  - Talens, H., 1933-1934 (Folder 7: 62)
  - Teissonnière, Paul, n.d. (Folder 7: 63)
  - Telegraaf, De, Amsterdam, 1909-1929., See also Holdert; Schröder; Vandermeeren; Verbiest (Folder 7: 64)
  - Temperley, A. C., 1922 (Folder 7: 65)
  - Temps, Le, Paris, 1916 (Folder 7: 66)
  - Terhell(?), Herman, 1934 (Folder 7: 67)
  - Terlinden, C., Viscount, 1936 (Folder 7: 68)
  - Tetterode, J. P., 1914-1915 (Folder 7: 69)
  - Teylingen, C. J., 1914 (Folder 7: 70)
  - Thal, Larsen, J. H., 1936 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Thompson, Slason, 1917 (Folder 8: 2)
  - Thomson, Basil H., 1916-1919 (Folder 8: 3)
  - Thornton, M., 1937 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Three Arts Club, London, 1916-1925 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Thys(?), Frans, 1933-1935 (Folder 8: 6)
  - Tiffany, Katrina E., 1917 (Folder 8: 7)
  - Toudoze, Georges G., 1925-1927 (Folder 8: 8)
  - Touring Club de Belgique, Brussels, 1919 (Folder 8: 9)
  - Touzot, C., 1925-1926 (Folder 8: 10)
  - Tree, Viola, 1916 (Folder 8: 11)
  - Treub Boellaard, C., 1923 (Folder 8: 12)
  - Trösch, P. Ernst, 1915 (Folder 8: 13)
  - Twentieth Century Club, 1917 (Folder 8: 14)
  - Twilight Club, New York, 1917 (Folder 8: 15)
  - Uitgevers-Maatschappy ‘Elsevier,' Amsterdam, 1917-1919 (Folder 8: 16)
  - Union de la Presse Etrangère, Brussels, 1927 (Folder 8: 17)
  - Union Française pour le Suffrage des Femmes, Paris, 1916 (Folder 8: 18)
  - United States. Navy Department. Bureau of Navigation, Washington, D.C., 1919 (Folder 8: 19)
  - Université de Paris-Sorbonne, 1919 (Folder 8: 20)
  - Uzanne, Joseph, 1916 (Folder 8: 21)
  - Vandermeeren, G., 1915 (Folder 8: 22)
  - Veen, J. B. M. van, 1915 (Folder 8: 23)
  - Veer, John C. van der, 1914 (Folder 8: 24)
  - Veniselo, E. K., 1923-1928 (Folder 8: 25)
  - Verbiest, J., 1926-1929 (Folder 8: 26)
  - Vereeniging "St. Lucas," Amsterdam, 1910-1919 (Folder 8: 27)
  - Vereeniging van Vernis- en Verffabrikanten en -Handelaren in Nederland, Amsterdam, 1935 (Folder 8: 28)
  - Vereeniging voor Vrouwven -Kiesrecht, Amsterdam, 1914-1915 (Folder 8: 29)
  - Verein der Plakatfreunde, Charlottenburg, 1916 (Folder 8: 30)
  - Verschoor, Pierre, 1934 (Folder 8: 31)
  - Verster, C. W. H., 1914 (Folder 8: 32)
  - Vertommen, Armand, 1931-1932 (Folder 8: 33)
  - Veth, Cornelis, 1908 (Folder 8: 34)
  - Vigilantes, The, New York, 1917 (Folder 8: 35)
  - Viollier, Georges, 1917 (Folder 8: 36)
  - Visser and Co., Amsterdam, 1933 (Folder 8: 37)
  - Voor Jong Nederland, Amsterdam, 1933 (Folder 8: 38)
  - Voorhoeve, J. J., 1924 (Folder 8: 39)
  - Voorthuis, Evert, 1914 (Folder 8: 40)
  - Vos, N., 1914 (Folder 8: 41)
  - Voüte, M. P., 1935 (Folder 8: 42)
  - Vredenburch, J. van, 1927-1928 (Folder 8: 43)
  - Vreedenberg van Vossen, A. C. J., 1915 (Folder 8: 44)
  - Vuille, Charles, 1916-1917 (Folder 8: 45)
  - Waifs and Strays Society, London, 1917 (Folder 8: 46)
  - Walker Art Gallery, Liverpool, 1918-1919 (Folder 8: 47)
  - Wallace, Captain, 1915-1917 (Folder 8: 48)
  - Wallach, Sidney, 1934 (Folder 8: 49)
  - War Relief Fund - British Prisoners of War in Germany, London, 1917 (Folder 8: 50)
  - Weghe, C. van de, 1933 (Folder 8: 51)
  - Wenz, Paul, 1917 (Folder 8: 52)
  - Wermeskeren, Henri van, 1926 (Folder 8: 53)
  - Westermann, C. J., 1914 (Folder 8: 54)
  - Westland, Cora, 1915 (Folder 8: 55)
  - Westwood, H. R., 1915., See also Review of Reviews (Folder 8: 56)
  - Whitefriars Club, London, 1917-1920 (Folder 8: 57)
  - Whitlock, Brand, 1921 (Folder 8: 58)
  - Wibaut, F. M., 1921., See also N.V. Em. Queriso's Uitgevers-Mij (Folder 8: 59)
  - Wibaut, J. P., 1914 (Folder 8: 60)
  - Willeboordse, L., 1915 (Folder 8: 61)
  - Willem Weissenbruch, 1914 (Folder 8: 62)
  - Willems-Wetselaar, E. G., 1916 (Folder 8: 63)
  - Wilson, Charles, 1923-1925 (Folder 8: 64)
  - Wilson, Louis N. (Clark University Library, Worcester, Mass.), 1916-1917 (Folder 8: 65)
  - Wilson, Margaret, 1918 (Folder 8: 66)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1917 (Folder 8: 67)
  - Women's War Time Fund, London, 1916 (Folder 8: 68)
  - Woolmington, 1929 (Folder 8: 69)
  - World Peace Prayer Conference, Shanghai, 1935-1936 (Folder 8: 70)
  - Wouters, Henri, 1915 (Folder 8: 71)
  - Wullus Rudiger, A., 1934-1937 (Folder 8: 72)
  - Zapp, Rudolph de, 1917 (Folder 8: 73)
  - Zimmerman, A. R., 1927-1934 (Folder 8: 74)
  - Zoetelief-Tromp, J., 1923 (Folder 8: 75)
  - Zutphen, Jan A. van, 1937 (Folder 8: 76)
  - Zutphensche Kunstvereeniging ‘Pictura,' Zutphen, 1935 (Folder 8: 77)
  - Zwartendyk, J., 1917-1925 (Folder 8: 78)
  - Zweerts, P. F. C. J., 1923 (Folder 8: 79)
- Speeches and Writings, 1919-1928. (Box 8)
  Letters to the editor and speech, arranged chronologically
  - Letter to the editor re the so-called Polish Corridor, n.d. (Folder 8: 80)
  - Speech before the Lord Mayor of London at the Mansion House, 1919 April 7 (Folder 8: 81)
  - Letter to the editor, Times, 1920 February 8 (Folder 8: 82)
  - Letter to the editor, Review of Reviews, 1928 June 26 (Folder 8: 83)
- Subject File, 1915-1929. (Box 9)
  Clippings and printed matter arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Art (Folder 9: 1)
  - Cavell, Edith - Funeral service, 1919 (Folder 9: 2)
  - Eeden, Frederik van (Folder 9: 3)
  - Hearst newspapers (Folder 9: 4)
  - Miscellany (Folder 9: 5)
  - Muyden y Morel-Fatio, Arnold van (Folder 9: 6)
  - Ossietzky-Comite (Folder 9: 7)
  - San Francisco Bomb Case, Preparedness Parade, 1916 July 22 (Folder 9: 8)
  - Serbia - History - 1914-1918 (Folder 9: 9)
  - Telegraaf, De, Amsterdam (Folder 9: 10)
  - United States. Army
    - American Expeditionary Force, France, International Mess of the 42nd Division, 1918 (Folder 9: 11)
    - Enlistment, 1918 (Folder 9: 12)
- Newspaper Issues, 1911-1939. (Box 9)
  Arranged alphabetically by title of newspaper
  - Daily Palo Alto Times, 1918 (Folder 9: 13)
  - Haarlem's Dagblad, 1924 (Folder 9: 14)
  - Het Nieuws van den Dag, Amsterdam, 1939 (Folder 9: 15)
  - Phare, Le, Nantes, 1922 (Folder 9: 16)
  - Soir, Le, Brussels, 1922 (Folder 9: 17)
  - Telegraaf, De, Amsterdam, 1923 (Folder 9: 18)
  - World Magazine, New York, 1911 (Folder 9: 19)
- Scrapbooks, 1906-1930. (Box 10-14)
  Clippings about Raemaekers, arranged alphabetically by country and therein chronologically
  - American clippings
    - 1915-1916
    - 1915-1917
  - Dutch clippings (Box 11)
    - 1906-1915
    - 1915-1916.
      Includes some English clippings
    - 1916-1930
  - English clippings (Box 12)
    - 1916-1927
    - 1917-1919
  - French clippings (Box 13)
    - 1915 September-December
    - 1916
      - January-July
      - August-December.
        Includes some German, Russian, and Italian clippings
    - 1917-1929 (Box 14)
    - 1922-1923 (Le Phare)
- Miscellany, 1915-1940. (Box 15)
  Clippings, magazines, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically
  - General. (Folder 15: 1)
    Includes advertisements, leaflets, and programs, 1916-1930
  - Clippings
    - Hearst newspapers, 1917 (Folder 15: 2-3)
    - Stanford Bulletin, 1940 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Magazines, 1915-1924 (Folder 15: 5-8)
- Oversize Materials 1914-1917. (Box 16-20)
  Albums, books, cigarette cards, postcards, and stamps, arranged alphabetically
  - Albums (Box 16)
    - Autographs, n.d.
    - Clippings of cartoons that appeared in the Amsterdam Telegraaf, 1914-1915
    - Series of reproductions in Het Toppunt deer Beschaving, 1914-1917
  - Books (Box 17)
    - The Century Edition De Luxe of Raemaekers' War Cartoons, vol. 1-2, The Century Co., 1917, limited edition No. 377 with foreword by Theodore Roosevelt. Includes review of book in Land and Water, 1917
    - The Great War in 1916: A Neutral's Indictment, The Fine Art Society, Ltd., 1917, signed limited edition (Box 18)
    - Prisonniers de Guerre by Jean-Pierre Laurens, 1918
    - Raemaekers' Cartoons With Accompanying Notes By Well-Known English Writers, Doubleday, Page & Company, 1917., See also OVERSIZE FILE/ Advertisement
  - Books of postcards entitled Dessins d'un neutre, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Cigarette cards, n.d.
  - Loose postcards, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Stamps with war scenes by Raemaekers, n.d.
- Small Format Artwork, World War, 1914-1918. (Box 21-22)
  Landscapes, political cartoon, and sketches, arranged alphabetically and therein by country, continent, or topic, then artwork medium, then language, then title
  - Landscapes (urban and rural) affected by war, and sketches of battle scenes
    - Pencil drawings (Folder 21: 1-34)
    - Watercolors (Folder 21: 35-39)
  - Political cartoon. (Folder 21: 40)
    Pencil
  - Portrait sketches of soldiers, nurses, and civilians
    - Pencil drawings (Folder 21: 41-116)
    - Watercolors (Folder 21: 117-137)
    - Watercolors (Box-folder 22: 1-13)
  - Sketches of soldiers in battle, military and civilian life behind the front lines, and machines of war
    - Pencil drawings (Folder 22: 14-91)
    - Watercolors (Folder 22: 92-104)
- Medium Format Artwork, 1914-1945. (Box 23-40)
  Political cartoons and sketches, arranged alphabetically and therein by country, continent, or topic, then artwork medium, then language, then title
  - Political cartoons (Box 23)
    - Axis powers (Germany, 1933-1945; Italy, 1922-1945).
      Pencil and charcoal
      - Untitled and unidentified (Folder 23: 1)
      - Dutch language (Folder 23: 2-10)
      - English language. "Don't you worry, we'll carefully respect the western half" (Folder 23: 11)
      - French language
        - "L'axe Rome Berlin au ralenti" (Folder 23: 12)
        - "Les questions anglaises du 19 novembre, ou la mémoire retrouvée" (Folder 23: 13)
    - Balkans, 1918-1939. (Folder 23: 14)
      Pencil and charcoal. "De vredes-nargileh in den Balkan"
    - Belgium.
      - 1914-1918
        - Untitled and unidentified (Folder 23: 15)
        - Dutch language (Folder 23: 16)
      - 1918-1939
        - Dutch language (Folder 23: 17-24)
        - French language
          - "Les crédits militaires votés" (Folder 23: 25)
          - "Vider le coffer-fort de toute la nation pour remplir les poches de quelques-uns" (Folder 23: 26)
          - "Vos obligations sont changées, mon devoir reste!" (Folder 23: 27)
          - "Votre contribution y est-elle? Comité National de Secours: Il doit y en avoir pour tous les nécessiteux!" (Folder 23: 28)
          - "Zone démilitarisée... Devère: Hm! Nous allons démilitariser notre zone.. ." (Folder 23: 29)
    - Bulgaria, 1918-1939. (Folder 23: 30)
      Pencil and charcoal - Dutch language
    - Czechoslovakia, 1918-1939. (Folder 23: 31-32)
    - East Asia, 1918-1939. (Box 24)
      - Dutch language (Folder 24: 1-26)
      - English language
        - "Happy ending? Tientsin" (Folder 24: 27)
        - "How peaceful it all looks, but how long will it last?" (Folder 24: 28)
        - "Lord Lytton to Japan: I am only putting things in order" (Folder 24: 29)
        - "Uncle Sam: ‘Who said Pacific?'" (Folder 24: 30)
      - French language
        - "Les deux parties en Espagne à bout de forces" (Folder 24: 31)
        - "L'évolution du ‘Danger Jaune'" (Folder 24: 32)
        - "Les trois quarts sont pour une politique de paix..." (Folder 24: 33)
    - Egypt, 1918-1939. (Folder 24: 34)
    - Europe, 1918-1939.
      Relations between the European powers, including international conferences, negotiations and treaties, and the Communist and Nazi threats. Pencil and charcoal
      - Untitled and unidentified (Folder 25: 1)
      - Dutch language (Folder 25: 2-67)
      - English language (Box 26)
        - "Asking for it" (Folder 26: 1)
        - "French-Russian non aggression pact" (Folder 26: 2)
        - "International Beauty Parlour Eden-Delbos & Cy." (Folder 26: 3)
        - "Locarno. John: You will get a new one. Marianne: A more solid one?" (Folder 26: 4)
        - "The writing on the wall" (Folder 26: 5)
      - French language
        - "Assurances gratuites" (Folder 26: 6)
        - "Les avions du III-ème Reich.. ." (Folder 26: 7)
        - "Ballet russe" (Folder 26: 8)
        - "Conseil de l'ami Lloyd George" (Folder 26: 9)
        - "Coup de filet d'espions nazis" (Folder 26: 10)
        - "De la blonde à la brune" (Folder 26: 11)
        - "De la brune à la blonde" (Folder 26: 12)
        - "Déclaration anglo-française à Genève" (Folder 26: 13)
        - "La démocratie ne doit pas devenir la terre nourricière du communisme" (Folder 26: 14)
        - "L'éclaircie après une période d'orage" (Folder 26: 15)
        - "Eden: ‘Enfin, quel gage nous proposez-vous, pour qu'un nouveau pacte sera respecté?'.. ." (Folder 26: 16)
        - "L'enlèvement de l'Europe" (Folder 26: 17)
        - "L'entrevue Samuel Hoare - Laval" (Folder 26: 18)
        - "L'Europe Centrale et sa dernière ligne de sauvetage: L'Entente Cordiale" (Folder 26: 19)
        - "Femmes de France et de Belgique: Merci! Monsieur Chamberlain" (Folder 26: 20)
        - "Golgotha et Pàques" (Folder 26: 21)
        - "Grock nous revient" (Folder 26: 22)
        - "Guerre espagnole?" (Folder 26: 23)
        - "Il n'y a rien de changé!" (Folder 26: 24)
        - "Le lancement du croiseur inconnu" (Folder 26: 25)
        - "Les ministres cabotins extrémistes qui voudraient remplacer son idéologie par les leurs" (Folder 26: 26)
        - "Monétaire acrobatie" (Folder 26: 27)
        - "Le nouveau ‘Big Stick' " (Folder 26: 28)
        - "Les offres à la Hollande et la Belgique" (Folder 26: 29)
        - "Plan quinquennal anglais.. ." (Folder 26: 30)
        - "La position de Laval" (Folder 26: 31)
        - "Pourquoi les fortifications?" (Folder 26: 32)
        - "Le projet Devère accepté à l'unanimité" (Folder 26: 33)
        - "Salon de beauté international: Traitement aux rayons infra-rouges" (Folder 26: 34)
      - German language
        - "Vorschlag zur Güte" (Folder 26: 35)
        - "Vorschlag zur Güte" (different image) (Folder 26: 36)
      - Italian language. (Folder 26: 37)
        "Fascismo e salvezza"
    - France, 1918-1939 (Box 27)
      - Untitled and unidentified (Folder 27: 1-3)
      - Dutch language (Folder 27: 4-30)
      - French language
        - "D'abord nous!" (Folder 27: 31)
        - "Le doigt sur... la plaie" (Folder 27: 32)
        - "Liberté, liberté chérie" (Folder 27: 33)
        - "Marianne: Mon Dieu, quelle saleté!" (Folder 27: 34)
        - "Les troubles en France" (Folder 27: 35)
        - "Vive la République!" (Folder 27: 36)
      - German language
        - "Das grössere "Übel" (Folder 27: 37)
        - "Man meint zu schieben... und man wird geschoben" (Folder 27: 38)
        - "Nur wer die Sehnsucht kennt weiss was ich leide!" (Folder 27: 39)
    - Germany, 1918-1939 (Box 28)
      - Pencil and charcoal
        - Untitled and unidentified (Folder 28: 1)
        - Dutch language (Folder 28: 2-19)
        - French language
          - "L'Angleterre dénonce la menace des armements excessifs" (Folder 28: 20)
          - "Les deux oeufs-de-PAX" (Folder 28: 21)
          - "Le discours du Géneral Göring" (Folder 28: 22)
          - "En recherche d'un gros emprunt" (Folder 28: 23)
          - "Et à Berlin" (Folder 28: 24)
          - "La paix est indivisible" (Folder 28: 25)
          - "Paix teutonique: Versailles, Locarno, zÔne démilitarisée" (Folder 28: 26)
          - "'La parité' aérienne allemande" (Folder 28: 27)
          - "La parole est à l'accusé" (Folder 28: 28)
          - "Restauration des Habsbourgs en Autriche..." (Folder 28: 29)